CJ Entertainment Presents
A Woojeung Film Production
In Association with Light Green Pictures
Executive Producer JEONG Tae-sung
Co-executive Producer Michelle KWON
Produced by LEE Woo-jeung
"This film is based on actual events."
"However, certain incidents
have been fictionalized,"
"and the film is not intended as
an accurate re-enactment."
"Korea News"
"President Chun Today"
President Chun visited
police headquarters today
to award medals to officers
who apprehended North Korean spies.
The President expressed concerns
about the recent resurgence of
violent anti-state movements
instigated by radical left subversives,
and emphasized the importance of
protecting social order and national security.
What is it?
"Director Park
Head of Anti-communist Investigations"
"North Korean-born, crossed into the South"
Open the gates.
"12:30PM Jan 14, 1987"
"Namyeong-dong
Anti-communist Division Facility"
Inspector.
"Dr. Oh Yun-sang
Physician at Chung-Ang Hospital"
He's dead.
Bring him back.
Give me a cardiotonic.
Start the engine.
Sir, we have a situation.
Director's on his way.
He can't be resuscitated.
Move the body.
Come on.
I'm sorry.
Hold it properly!
Eradicate communism!
Come on.
Who called the doctor?
I did, sir.
He was just a testifier, so...
Without reporting first?
You realize you made a witness.
What are you gonna do about this?
No need to fuss over nothing.
Go have lunch.
Attention!
Eradicate communism!
What should we do with the body?
Burn it.
As you command, sir.
Welcome.
Attention! Salute!
Eradicate communism!
Congratulations, Director.
I'm sorry I missed the ceremony.
"Director Jang / Head of Intelligence Agency"
"President's right-hand man"
The President wanted to
give this to you in person but...
It's an honor either way.
What have you got for me?
Kim Jung-Nam?
He's the one behind a series of
communist activities of late.
He doesn't hold rank or have a title.
He wrote the decree for democratization
issued by the opposition leaders,
Kim Young-Sam and Kim Dae-Jung.
You want to bring all of them
in a single package?
If I can prove that
they're supporters of Kim ll-sung,
we can wipe out those challenging
the reinstatement of the President.
You sure live up to your reputation.
The master of the Blue House may
come and go but you remain strong.
This man needs to be apprehended
before the new university semester.
Of course.
"Prosecutor Choi
Seoul District Prosecutor's Office"
You said 5PM before!
Are you messing with me?
I don't remember.
I can't even remember what I had for lunch.
Look at you, filling the sacred
soju bottles with gasoline...
-It's not gasoline.
-What is it then?
It's paint thinner.
Don't get smart with me.
-Food delivery.
-In there.
What else am I supposed to call it?
Having fun hanging out here?
Your parents must be so damn proud of you.
You little shit.
I'm screwed whatever I say.
Oh, no!
You shouldn't be eating that crap.
What brings you here at this hour?
Come with us.
I'll treat you to a proper dinner.
Sounds like an idea.
Where are we going?
Can you sign this for us?
No such thing as a free drink.
Using dirty tricks on me now?
Come on, Prosecutor.
Park Jong-chul, Seoul National University...
Died of a heart attack?
A 22-year-old?
Needs to be cremated tonight.
I'll get going.
Do stay and enjoy the rest of the night.
You deserve some down time.
There won't be any problems
with that dead college kid, right?
Sure.
It's being taken care of.
"Authorization for cremation"
He's been dead for less than 8 hours.
Has the family seen the body?
They haven't, have they?
We obtained consent from his father
at the Busan Police Station.
Who would agree to have his son cremated
without even seeing the body?
Who are you trying to kid?
This is Anti-communist matter. Just sign it.
Don't fucking tell me what to do.
Take the paper and get out.
Come on, cut us some slack.
Just sign the paper and let's get out of here.
All expense paid.
This is so sloppy that you're making me blush.
You need an autopsy before burial or cremation.
That's the law.
Yes, we know that.
But the powers-that-be
want this wrapped up by morning.
What...
What powers?
The Intelligence Agency?
The Blue House?
Man
Help us out here.
Do the autopsy in the morning,
have it cremated by afternoon.
Damn, all soggy now.
See you again.
The crematorium is closed now anyway.
This'll put your father-in-law
in a difficult position.
I know that but...
Don't make it hard for everyone.
Just do as you're told.
Yes sir.
There's someone here to see you.
I thought you had a dinner to go to.
It's hard to eat
when the Blue House is calling.
What's wrong with you?
Those Anti-communist thugs think
they're above everyone.
I wanted to teach them a lesson.
Who are you trying to teach?
Think this is funny?
Sign the document, or we're in for shit.
I'll handle this my way, sir.
I don't care how high up your father-in-law is.
If I get another call,
I'll fucking sign it myself.
ls that clear?
I'll sign it.
I thought it might be an important call.
"Restraining order against cremation"
Lay a finger on that body,
and I'll have your asses.
Prosecutor Choi!
Prosecutor!
Open the door.
Open it, dammit!
What took you so long?
"Prosecutor Lee
The Supreme Prosecutor's Office"
You slow ass...
I'm so damn busy nowadays,
I don't even have time
to wash my hands after toilet.
You never do anyway.
Do I deserve
all this love and attention from you?
Come on, let's get dinner.
Does your wife still make that soup of hers?
I can't go home.
What did you do this time?
Nothing yet. But I'll wind up
breaking something if I go home.
Who pissed you off this time?
Those little shits down
at the Anti-communist Investigations
act like they're above prosecutors.
They think they're tough shit.
But who dares question their authority?
I'll just screw them
and hand in my resignation.
They won't bat an eyelid. It's not worth it.
Speaking of which,
I need a favor from you.
A favor?
Good play!
Good game.
Good job.
Your ball is so fast.
Looks like that new tonic
you're taking is a fountain of youth.
We can't find Prosecutor Choi.
We even checked motels in the area.
ls he a commie?
I just don't understand.
Put me through to the DA.
"7:30AM Jan 15, 1987"
"Seoul District Prosecutor's Office"
Sir, Prosecutor Choi is missing.
That pain in the ass!
Get some men out and find him.
Yes sir.
God almighty!
You pain in the ass...
Hey, Choi! Get up!
-Morning, sir.
-Did you sleep well?
Director Park
called me first thing this morning.
I don't like where this is going.
Just close the case and move on.
I have to have that autopsy.
Park is nobody to mess with.
I haven't seen a single man
who survived pissing him off.
Remember that sexual torture case?
We went along with what they said,
and wound up eating shit for ourselves.
I wanna do this one right.
Stop any man on the street
and dig into his family tree,
there's bound to be at least one North Korean.
Know who you're dealing with.
All the circumstances point to
death by torture.
All the more reason to stay out of it.
If it goes public, it'll be a shit storm that
none of us can handle.
Exactly.
That's why we gotta do this right.
Why are you such a stubborn pain in my ass?
Blame it on me,
the insubordinate ass-pain that ran wild.
That'll keep your hands clean.
Sure about this?
Of course not.
What?
But I know one thing for sure.
Nothing like whiskey for breakfast.
I knew it.
What do I do about you?
It all worked out then?
Morning, Shin.
Morning, Prosecutor Lee.
Yes.
Okay.
I understand.
You've got nothing to worry about.
First to arrive, as always.
Early bird gets the worm.
Thank you.
Those cops are in deep shit.
The kid was a college student.
Sorry?
"Shin Sung-ho / Reporter with Joongang Daily"
Yeah, yeah.
The law student, right?
No, not law school.
He was in linguistics.
His name was Park...something or other.
Right. Linguistics.
What a waste of precious life.
Those Anti-communist thugs
run around like rabid dogs.
They are so...out of control.
Hello? Chief?
An SNU student died
during an anti-communist interrogation.
My son is here? Why?
-There's been an accident.
-What?
Let's go inside.
Why did you bring me to the morgue?
Honey...what are you doing here?
What's going on?
Where's Jong-chul?
Jong-chul...
Jong-chul!
Oh my God...My baby!
Smells good.
You're eating now?
"9 labor activists arrested"
"Yoon Sang-Sam / Journalist with Dong-A Daily"
Sang-Sam wrote a killer article
on the labor activist movement.
A beautiful piece of work.
What's the point?
We can only print what they allow us.
It's the stuff between the lines, pops.
Leaving some room for interpretation.
Not when they spell it out for you.
You're prickly today.
Fought with the wife again?
Joongang Daily!
Just say you're sorry.
Joongang's late today.
"3:00PM Jan 15, 1987
Prosecutor's press room"
Let's see how their dictation is.
Shit! Come on.
-What's going on?
-What?
-Not the front page.
-The current affairs section!
I can't fucking believe this.
-Where is it?
-Which hospital?
"SNU student snuffed during police questioning"
Chief, I just saw the article.
Who cross checked the info?
That's the least of my worries!
The military just stormed into our offices.
What?
You said you checked all the facts.
They don't care about that!
We violated journalism guidelines.
Find somewhere to lay low and stay there.
If they catch you, you'll be beaten to death.
Do you hear me?
I found him!
-What the hell?
-Come here!
What the hell? Let go!
Let got of me!
I'm so sorry, sir!
I'll do everything in my power
to contain the situation, sir!
"Commissioner General / Police headquarters"
It seems we've worked ourselves into a corner.
Things like this happen
while conducting national affairs.
It'll work itself out.
Shut up, Park!
It could cost us our necks!
Cut out the ego bullshit.
Sit down.
The President threw the papers to the floor.
This is serious.
We gotta put out the fire.
Read this at the press briefing.
"Leftist student dies of heart attack"
So that's what happened.
And I swear on the honor of the police,
"4:00PM Jan 15, 1987
Commissioner General's Office"
there was no excessive force employed.
Then how did he die?
Well, it seems that...
during the investigation,
the investigator slammed his hands on...
on the table and...
The student was terrified.
So when the investigator
slammed his hands on the table, he just...
dropped dead.
Does that make any sense?
Dying from someone
slamming their hands on a table?
The official cause of death is heart attack.
A perfectly healthy young man
had a heart attack
by sudden shock?
As confirmed by a doctor
from Chung-Ang Hospital.
What's the doctor's name?
His name?
Oh, what was it...?
It hasn't been confirmed yet.
Of course it has.
The doctor's name is Oh Yun-sang.
-Did you get that?
-Oh Yun-sang, Chung-Ang Hospital.
-Go to Chung-Ang Hospital!
-Find Oh Yun-sang!
I said too much, didn't I?
Sorry...
"Chung-Ang University Hospital"
Out of my way!
So he died of heart attack from sudden shock?
I can't comment
until the autopsy has been completed.
Was he still alive at the ER?
He didn't come to the ER.
I saw him in Namyeong-dong...
Namyeong-dong?
What did you do?
I arrived after the cardiac arrest occurred.
Give us more details.
I arrived at the scene,
dried the body, then checked the -
The kid was wet?
We need details!
Are you saying the body was wet?
The detectives said...
that the deceased was heavily intoxicated,
so he drank a lot of water
during the investigation.
He was heavily intoxicated?
He'd been drinking rice wine...
Who is he kidding?
So did he die of shock or not?
What should I write?
He didn't give us anything.
We'll be given guidelines anyway.
Do you know any doctor?
Not anyone that can give an interview.
-Stay right here, understood?
-Yes sir.
Where's the restroom?
"4:00PM Jan 15, 1987
Hanyang Hospital"
Good afternoon, Prosecutor.
Did you bring enough roll films?
I brought 10 with me.
Good. That's great.
I'm a medical examiner
for the National Crime Lab.
I'll be witnessing.
This is a very sensitive case,
so please do everything by the book.
Make sure to leave no detail out.
ls this necessary?
It's just a formality.
"Prosecutor Pyo
Seoul District Prosecutor's Office"
ls that how you do your job?
I apologize.
Let's go.
Who are you people?
You can't come in here.
So piss off.
We have an official order for an autopsy.
We heard nothing about it,
so it's not happening.
I'm a public prosecutor!
Oh, really? We're sorry for our insolence.
Jong-chul! Jong-chul!
Leave her alone!
Mom!
Let me see him for the last time.
This is my last chance.
-Get her outta here.
-Please just for a moment.
-Come on.
-Please for the last time!
Let me touch his hand!
What are you here for?
Did you smirk at me? I'll remember your faces.
Fucking thugs!
"KIM JUNG-NAM SPY RING"
"Arrested"
"Kim Jung-Nam"
I think you should take this.
Who is this?
This is Prosecutor Choi
with the Seoul District Prosecutor's Office.
I'm at Hanyang Hospital,
and your men are refusing to cooperate.
I've been through this
with the necessary people.
That autopsy isn't happening.
Old man, I don't like your condescending tone.
I'm the Director
of Anti-communist Investigations.
And that puts you above the law?
Should I send over
some of my boys to teach you?
What did you say?
Open your books
and check who has the jurisdiction here.
And you better lose that accent
before you're mistaken for Kim ll-sung.
Get the car out.
Yes sir.
That crazy fucker!
This is the official order for the autopsy.
Nice work hiding behind a piece of paper.
Let's not make a scene.
We'll do this by the book.
If hunting dogs miss their target
while fighting among themselves,
who do you think
the master is going to punish for this?
I consider myself a stray
without a master.
You better watch yourself.
I'm liable to bite anyone.
ls that right?
But only your jaws will hurt.
Wait.
My wife's cousin...
just married a journalist
from this foreign newspaper.
Peter Henderson something or other.
He's been hounding me for a story.
The President would be quite upset
to read about this in the foreign press
before the Seoul Olympics.
What is it that you want?
Just wanna do my job right.
Alright. Go for it.
It's not going to change anything.
Let's get out of here.
I'm doing the autopsy.
I got your neck.
Go wander the streets
with the rest of the strays.
I guess I just dug my own grave.
I'll have to drink soju from now.
"9:50PM Jan 15, 1987"
"Hanyang Hospital"
Are you with the victim's family?
Your name, please.
Park Wol-Gil, I'm Jong-chul's uncle.
Please take a seat.
Shall we?
I'm going to the restroom.
Doctor, I'm a journalist with Dong-A Daily.
Did you see any signs of torture?
I waited here for too long.
You said the body was wet.
What was the condition of the body?
Just tell me what you saw.
Doctor!
There was water everywhere on the floor.
There was a bath tub in the room.
I heard crackling in the lungs.
Crackles?
Do you confirm the cause of death?
Yes...
No pictures!
-Mr. Park!
-Any comments?
The police murdered him!
My nephew didn't die of shock.
He was murdered!
He was killed during torture, wasn't he?
He was tortured with water, right?
This is what you'll say
when you give your statement tomorrow.
But I only dropped by to give them a hand.
There are formalities to go through.
Think of it as an early vacation.
I don't deserve this.
How dare you question my authority?
I did everything exactly as I was told.
-Why should I...
-Han-kyung.
Yes, Director.
Just go along with it.
As you command, sir.
We gotta run the story before
they wipe it under the carpet.
I even got my arm broken!
Will you take the responsibility?
-We should be responsible?
-For what?
-You alright, man?
-What happened?
-Let's go.
-Where are you going?
Attention, everyone!
From tomorrow,
we're running a special on torture prevention.
Launch a task force to find out
who killed him and how.
"No reporting on college student death"
What about the guidelines?
Fuck that!
Just fuck it
The police tortured and killed a student!
I don't give a rat's ass
about goddamn guidelines.
Yes sir.
Dr. Hwang!
I really appreciate
you going through all of this.
Take a seat.
How'd it go?
The cause of death was asphyxiation
due to airway obstruction.
The victim's windpipe was crushed during tor-
Watch your mouth!
If you say that boy was tortured,
you'll pretty much
sign all of our death warrants.
But there are marks all over the body.
That'll be taken care of
once the body is cremated.
Just put 'heart attack' in the report.
Here, take some down time with your team.
I'm sorry, Commissioner.
You're digging your own grave.
I'm announcing it as heart attack.
"9:00AM Jan 1 6, 1 987"
A pulmonary hemorrhage in his right lung,
is most likely a result of TB.
The contusions on the throat and chest
are remnants of efforts at resuscitation.
Thus, there were no signs of
unnecessary force or brutality.
Jong-chul!
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Mom...
My son's not a commie...
Mom...mom!
Vehicle #2 on the move.
You're obstructing journalists!
Align shields!
Let us through!
Lift shields!
Mr. Park!
U-turn here?
Wait, wait.
Give me the camera.
But the bus is going straight.
No, not straight.
-What are they doing?
-Which car is which?
2382...
Left! Make a left.
Left?
Let's go.
Move your damn car!
Get out of the way!
Hey! Hey! Stop them.
Stop the car!
-I'm with Dong-A Daily.
-Stop, you rats!
You smashed our camera!
Don't touch me!
Why can't we cover the story?
Why not?
Jong-chul...
Dad...
Why can't you leave?
Can't you leave, my boy?
Why do you linger here?
Good bye, my son.
Dad has nothing to say to you.
I'm an accredited reporter!
No one's allowed in today.
More pain in the ass.
Just go, for fuck's sake!
Did you just swear at me?
Easy, Yoon.
Let me check some facts.
He died from drowning, didn't he?
Drowning, my ass.
What was it then? Death by excessive force?
Just tell me for god's sake!
Why should I tell you that?
It's your job to find out.
You're in this together.
They promised you something?
A place in the Intelligence? The Blue House?
Yeah, I'm trying to
ass-kiss my way up the ladder.
Shame on you.
"National Crime Lab"
"AUTOPSY REPORT: Park Jong-chul"
Do your dictation right.
"Died during water torture"
"Police headquarters' covert office"
"4:00PM Jan 1 9, 1 987"
This isn't the Internal Affairs office.
What's going on?
Cuff them.
Let go of me!
Let go!!!
Do not resist.
Back off!
You are arrested for murder
by the use of excessive force.
You are no longer police officers
but criminals.
You hear?
I had no choice.
The order came from the Blue House.
Where did you take them?
I can't tell you knowing what you'll do.
Brace yourself, Director Park.
Sometimes you gotta cut off the tail
to save the body.
It's the secret office in Shingil, sir.
Back off!
Director, please...
-Director!
-Sir!
You fucking heathens.
Release him now!
Stop what you're doing!
Do you realize you're disobeying a direct or-
You're disobeying orders
and assaulting superiors?
You think we're the same police, you and I?
While you and your men get fat off bribes,
I'm out there risking my life,
trying to bring down the commies.
This country would've been
devoured by Kim ll-sung if it wasn't for me.
Do you understand?
You're making a huge mistake.
If the President finds out about this -
Listen carefully.
Anyone that stands between me and the enemy
is an enemy himself.
Get 'em out of my sight.
Move it.
Does it hurt?
Not as much as my pride.
Lift your head.
You're a patriot. Don't ever cower.
They're accusing me of first degree murder.
That's a minimum 1 0 years.
I'll get the charges
reduced to involuntary manslaughter
then a suspended sentence.
I have five mouths to feed.
I'll take care of them too.
I'm counting on you, sir.
There.
You know I take care of my own.
"Han Byung-Yong
Guard at Yeongdeungpo Penitentiary"
"Fired for union activity then reinstated"
Can you tell those guys to quiet down?
They'll wake everyone.
"Lee Bu-young
Former reporter of Dong-A Daily"
"Imprisoned for leading the Incheon riots"
We're not allowed to go near them.
Are they on death row?
You know the cops that
killed that college student?
"Press we heaven-wards!"
"Press we on, bravely on!"
"Cast off doubt and fear!"
"Press we heaven-wards!"
Hey you, come here.
I said come here.
Show me your ID.
ls this all? Search him.
Got anything else?
Which bus goes to Pil-dong?
Stop!
I'm home.
Where have you been?
Going around looking for trouble?
You should be thinking about
getting married instead.
I've been out looking for a nice girl
to marry me.
So were you out on a date?
Were you, huh?
Wasting your time doing worthless things.
Will you leave me alone?
Are you hanging out
with those bad influences again?
I'm the bad influence.
It's not normal for someone my age
to live with his nagging sister.
There's stew inside. Go eat.
I ought to find a woman like you.
Oh, cut it out.
Okay.
What about Yeon-hee?
She's sleeping.
That's all she's been doing all day.
"I want to listen to this song
with my boyfriend," wrote this listener.
A song for anxious youth,
'The Veiled Path' by Yoo Jae-ha.
Damned old thing.
You won't break it like that. Want a hammer?
I told you to fix it, didn't I?
You sound more and more
like your mother every day.
Here. I found this in the trash.
What is it? Snacks?
A Walkman? Really?
Byung-Yong!
You're the best uncle ever.
Get away from me.
It's my college acceptance gift.
Yeon-hee.
And this...
You want me to meet him again?
I get stopped at the checkpoints every time.
They never stop you.
Wake up! You almost lost your job
by messing with that union business!
This isn't about the union.
Yeah, right.
This is really for a good cause.
I wouldn't ask you if it wasn't a good thing.
Sure about that?
Running an errand for a convict
is a good thing?
-Well, if you feel that way...
-Hey!
You said it was for me.
Du-bong also got into college.
-Who's that?
-My boss'son.
It's the last time, okay?
Deal.
You can record, too?
Check out auto-reverse.
Get outta here!
-Gimme that.
-Pass.
You, hey!
Attention! Stop daydreaming!
What the hell are you staring at, assholes?
-I'll leave you to it then.
-Thank you, Abbot.
What did you want to see me about?
"Ham Se-woong / Priest"
"Catholic Priests' Association for Justice"
"Kim Jung-Nam"
"Wanted for leading numerous democracy activists"
You're making a statement
demanding truth about the student's death?
We plan to do it tomorrow.
I suggest you don't mention
there're more officers involved.
If the police raise their guard even more,
getting to the bottom of the truth
will become difficult.
I heard the prison security section chief
is tough as nail.
Even the guards aren't allowed to talk to them.
We'll make it happen.
We'll find out the names and ranks
of everyone responsible for the death.
Father,
our only weapon is the truth.
And that truth
will bring down this administration.
Mr. Kim!
Yeon-hee!
Uncle says he's sorry he couldn't
deliver the news you've been waiting for.
I see.
You don't look like
you're here for Buddhist service.
You must be the ring leader behind all of this.
This is Yeon-hee. She's Guard Han's niece.
Turn yourself in,
and you will find the peace you seek.
Sir!
"Ahn Yoo / Security Section Chief"
"at Yeongdeungpo Penitentiary"
-Jin-gyu!
-Sweetheart...
-Baby!
Mom...
"4:30PM Feb 20, 1 987"
Dad.
You okay, son?
What have you done?
It's nothing, mom.
I'm going to figure it out.
You killed a man. How can you say it's nothing?
We didn't raise you like that.
Dad, it's not what you think.
You have to believe me.
What do you mean? Tell me what happened.
I only held his legs, but I didn't kill him.
It wasn't me! I didn't do it -
Get him out of here.
-Jin-gyu!
-Son!
Jin-gyu!
Please abide by visitor regulations.
If you write this again,
I'll blow up the goddamn place.
"Visitor's log"
This is Chief Ahn.
This is Han.
4879 requests for a meeting.
I'll be right there.
Good evening.
Chief Ahn.
I heard you requested a meeting.
ls there a problem?
I heard those new inmates
are causing a problem.
That's the prison's problem.
What are your complaints?
ls it true that
there are more cops involved in the torture?
If you have no complaints,
this interview is over.
You may stay a while longer, if you want.
Do you want to be an accomplice to their crime?
I'm not at liberty
to discuss information obtained on duty.
You can't keep the truth information
behind these bars!
My job is to protect and guard.
"2:00PM Mar 3, 1 987"
"49th day after Park Jong-chul's death"
What's the matter with him?
Jung-mi!
Urgh, you're late again!
Getting all prettied
up for blind date, obviously.
Do I look alright?
I just washed my face.
You have lipstick on your teeth.
Down with the student killers,
down with the torturers!
Wait, he's cute.
Citizens! Today, there will be...
a memorial service for Park.
Let's rise in protest!
Bring back, Park Jong-chul!
Please take one.
"Memorial march for the late Park Jong-chul"
Bring back, Park Jong-chul!
Come on, let's go.
I'm not a protester!
Goddamn commies!
Bitch!
Fucking bitch!
Wait.
Stop, you commies!
This way.
Hurry.
We're closed.
Come back later.
Pull the damn thing up.
I said we're closed, dammit!
Pull up the shutter!
Shut your mouth!
Damned protesters...
It was my first blind date.
Don't rub it with your hands. It'll sting more.
Wash it with water.
Your shoe...
I've still got my socks.
If you go out like that,
you're sure to get caught.
Size 9?
It's 8 dollars but you can take them for 5.
I'm sorry but I don't have money now.
Huh?
I got this.
No, it's okay.
Let her buy it!
Here.
I'm paying you back.
Oh god...
Hey, wait.
"Visitor's log"
I said no records, goddammit.
I'm cross-checking the statements
because they don't match.
You said that the victim had his hands cuffed
behind his back,
but we found no signs of cuffing
on the victim's wrists.
ls this necessary?
The charge is involuntary manslaughter.
Involuntary manslaughter?
Your charges are murder by torture!
The charges haven't been reduced?
In your dreams!
If you don't cooperate, I'll go for 15 years.
Better get your act straight.
Son of a bitch...
What did you say?
I didn't kill him.
What?
Are your deaf?
It wasn't me that killed him!
This isn't how it's supposed to go.
Inspector Cho!
Prosecutor, we'll resume in the near future.
What's going on here?
Tell Director Park
to meet his end of the bargain.
What the hell?
You want a piece of me?
You should be telling them that.
Why are you doing this, Cho?
It was you that killed an innocent kid, not me.
Grab him.
Don't you dare!
Your lives depend on my words.
Remember that.
This interview is over.
Fuck!
Sir.
What the hell are you retards doing?
Ministry of Culture!
Send out the new journalism guidelines.
The protests are about direct election.
That's what is causing
the senseless violence in the streets.
Yes sir.
Ministry of Interior.
Set up more checkpoints,
especially near universities.
Yes sir.
Increase CS gas production to full capacity.
Do I have to tell you every little thing?
I heard about what happened at the prison.
You must reduce the charges
to involuntary manslaughter.
We just managed to put out the fire,
and now you want to rekindle it.
"Park Jong-chul protests on rise"
It'll be a loose end if we don't.
I can postpone the trial indefinitely.
You figure out the rest.
The President is deeply concerned
about this matter.
Thousand, ten thousand...
hundred thousand dollars?
This for 1 0 years of my life?
I want out of here in a month.
After the President
passes down the presidency to his successor,
there'll be a presidential pardon.
You want me to wait until next year?
I've been fooled before.
I've got nothing to lose.
I'll tell the truth,
place my bet with the courts.
This is a very important time right now.
Be the patriot that -
Don't talk to me about patriotism!
I haven't had a single night of sleep here.
Even in the dark,
my ears are filled with screams.
Screams of those I hurt over the years!
Do you honestly think we're patriots?
You ungrateful bastard!
Back off!
I'll put a goddamn bullet in your face!
Do it.
Shoot me!
No, I have a better idea.
I'm going to throw your wife and children
in the Imjin River.
I'll say they tried to cross into North Korea.
You know exactly how it's done.
I'll make you live the rest of your life
in agonizing Hell.
Director...
Now choose.
Patriot or traitor?
I'll do as you say, sir.
I'll do what you want!
Director, this is far
beyond prison regulations.
Per regulations, visitors cannot -
come in physical contact with inmates.
You're trying real hard.
Take your boys out to drink.
Get in that line.
Pass.
Your student ID number?
871 1 023
I never got stopped before.
Seriously, do I look like an activist?
You kinda look like one today.
The perfect match for your protesting knight.
I told you, he's not an activist.
Are you kidding me? Of course, he is.
Anyway, he probably won't even recognize you.
Unless your makeup is all smeared.
-Want me to smudge it?
-Cut it out.
Learn from me,
and carry your books in your arms like this.
Innocent. Girlish. A college goddess.
It's pathetic hiding your breasts behind books.
There's no shame in having small breasts.
I don't have small boobs!
Holy crap!
That's him?
Communist or not, he's totally hot.
Oh, no!
He actually recognized you.
Smile.
Hi! You're a freshman?
Yes...
You can skip the intros.
It's not like you haven't met.
Oh, okay...
We're holding a video screening
if you wanna come.
Sorry?
We'll draw caricatures afterwards.
Sure. We'll be there.
By the way, nice sneakers. Are they new?
They're cheap though.
Thanks. See ya!
He doesn't recognize you at all.
He said they were cheap stuff.
I'm not going.
It's okay. He doesn't even know you.
I said I'm not going.
Okay, okay.
What...you're putting on makeup?
You're so annoying, you know that?
Welcome.
Please take a seat.
Shall we start?
Thank you for coming out.
We'll start the screening shortly.
What kind of movie is it?
It's a documentary. From abroad.
You all know about the Gwangju Uprising?
The truth is in here.
The first time I saw it,
I couldn't finish either.
I was so shocked -
Why are you showing this at a cartoon club?
What're you gonna do?
Fight the army?
If someone else dies,
who will be responsible then?
We've interrogated 22 men
about Kim Jung-nam's hideout,
but no luck so far.
"Kim Jung-soo"
You're sparing your bones?
"Kim Jung-nam's cousin"
I'm sorry but the boys' morale
isn't like before.
Attention!
This is Director Park.
Turn on the TV.
Presidential conference is starting soon.
Yes sir.
The President is waiting for
Kim Jung-nam's arrest.
Prove these political dissidents
are North Korean spies
and make Park Jong-chul case go away.
That's our only hope.
And your last chance.
"The Blue House"
Release them all.
At a time like this,
we gotta bring in more, not release them.
When I was living in the North,
I had a dog that used to run away.
You wanna know how I always found it?
I'd go for a walk with a female dog in heat.
Without fail, the runaway dog
would come out running and drooling.
I've decided that
it is impossible to revise the constitution
during my term.
"9:00AM Apr 1 3, 1 987"
"Declaration of prohibition
on constitutional debate"
In order to assure
a peaceful transition of power...
Kim can't help but crawl out of his hole now.
Use his bitches as baits.
As you command, sir.
Follow me.
...and those who seek to divide the nation...
That's bullshit. How can he do this?
Direct election is out of question.
This is a blatant extension of dictatorship.
What does this mean for us?
Get ready to be busy as hell.
Politics! Current Affairs! Gather up!
What does this mean?
He will choose the next President himself.
Fuck! One more soju here.
-Coming up.
-No, we're good.
You have a trial in an hour.
Fuck trial.
So he's gonna rule for another 7 years?
Not just 7. He'll hold power as long
He'll hold power
as long as they hold elections in the gym.
What's that mean?
Indirect elections, you dumb ass.
How did you get into college, man?
Goddamn fixed game.
What're you doing?
Something...anything.
Let me help. What're you thinking?
Fire up the printing press.
I gotta go out for a moment, Abbot.
It's too risky now.
What's the point of a direct election anyway?
This country isn't ready for democracy.
Get ready for your shifts!
I've got all of your backs.
Go out and find every commie supporter
you can find.
Eradicate them!
Eradicate communism!
We released Kim Jung-nam's bitches.
Prisoner 4789!
Request for meeting.
In here.
"Visitor's log Dialogue summary"
I had to write some of them from memory.
This is all I can do.
You have until morning call.
Stop there.
Me?
No rest for the weary, right?
I'm with the Ministry of Justice.
That's just my magazine.
You're a prison guard?
You look more like...
Like I belong on the other side of the bars.
I think the prisoners
leave a stink on me or something.
What's this?
I got it to help pass time.
Pass.
Thank you, officers.
-Nothing like the tabloid to kill time.
-Digest is better.
The Readers' Digest.
Bitch #6 just left the temple.
I thought Kim was Catholic.
So did I.
Go check it out.
You take the back.
Shouldn't we report it first?
Do you want someone else
to get the credit? Go on.
Target spotted!
Repeat, target spotted!
Around the back.
He's wearing workman's clothes.
I swear he was here.
Hey.
Get up there.
Where the fuck did he go?
Confirm position of the target.
He's not here.
Goddammit!
Get your asses up here. Now!
For crying out loud.
I'm sorry, sir.
Director!
Did Mr. Kim evacuate to safety?
He managed to give them a slip.
Thank goodness for that.
He's taking refuge in Hyanglim Church for now.
I know the place.
I'll visit him there...
No, no...
I'm home.
No, it'd be too risky for you
to contact him now.
Where's mom?
Jung-nam's statement will not have any effect
without that information.
Wait.
All our people are under heavy surveillance.
I'll find another way to pass on the message.
Yeon-hee.
Yeon-hee!
You scared me.
What do you want?
I'm not doing it.
I swear this is the last time.
It's important.
He needs to see this.
What's the point? Only you'll end up hurt.
How can I do nothing
when there's something I can do?
I'm not alone in this.
There are people working together.
Don't you know how my father died?
All his colleagues ran away
at the first sign of trouble.
He stood up for what was right.
The company that didn't pay the wages
should be blamed.
Not the others.
He didn't start drinking
because of the company.
He drank because of the people that
betrayed him.
Yeon-hee.
It was an accident.
It was no one's fault.
Bullshit!
If they hadn't abandoned him...
He wouldn't have died.
You can take this back.
It's 25 cents.
You're 5 cents short.
Go on, have a good life.
Careful, dears.
Where's your uncle?
I don't know.
Byung-Yong!
Help me move the stalls inside.
Did you two fight?
Of course not.
How many times do I have to tell you?
He's practically a father to you.
Oh my god!
Who are you people?
You little rat!
Byung-Yong!
No, don't!
-Get off me.
-Help!
Get off of me.
Come here.
Stop!
What's going on?
-I didn't do...
-Shut up!
Take him!
No!
Search the place.
Byung-Yong!
I'm okay. Don't worry.
-Uncle!
-Byung-Yong!
-Yeon-hee!
-Uncle!
How can they do this?
Did you see my men at the prison?
I've seen them a couple of times.
Do you know Kim Jung-Nam?
I don't know who that is.
Kim Jung-Nam received money from Kim ll-sung
and split it with the opposition leaders,
correct?
I...don't know that man.
"KIM JUNG-NAM SPY RING"
I thought you didn't know
who I was talking about.
Get him out of here.
Two cushions?
I'll show you how it's done.
Goal!
This room's got a history. A bad history.
So let's finish quickly
and walk out of here alive, okay?
Evening papers!
You live high up.
Why did you come here?
I came to recruit you, of course.
Join our cartoon club.
Jung-mi just joined too.
We made this at the club.
"Appeal against dictatorship and torture"
Are you going to protest?
You think you can change the world?
Your ideals and dreams...
Don't you think about your family?
"When the Day Comes"
No such day will come.
Stop dreaming and wake up.
I wish I could,
but I can't.
Because it hurts too much.
You should go.
See ya.
Yeon-hee!
Call me if you change your mind.
"Call me."
"This is my number!"
"This is the last time."
"It's really important."
"Find Kim Jung-Nam at Hyanglim Church. Please."
Hello?
Yeon-hee.
What's wrong, mom?
What happened?
Your uncle's been taken by
the same people that killed that student.
That bastard won't give in.
Can you do another round?
We worked him over 7 times,
and he still gave us nothing.
He's a tenacious bastard, huh?
Bring me his file.
What's going on?
Get out of my way!
I know he's here.
I'm here, Byung-Yong!
Your sister's here!
Stop them.
Give my brother back!
Keep these people out.
Are you alright?
Mom! You alright?
How dare you hit her?
What are you, some kind of thug?
Mom, no!
How dare you hit her?
Mom!
Shut up, you bitches!
To positions!
Sir!
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7
1 , 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
Do you see this kid standing next to my mother?
His name is Dong.
We found him starving to death,
so my mother took him in.
He was a bright kid.
My father took to him like a son.
He was like an older brother to me.
But when Kim ll-sung came into North Korea
Dong got fascinated by the idea
of people's democracy.
Do you know what he did to my family
in the name of the Red Army?
He called us the enemy!
Reactionaries and landowners!
To be sent to Hell!
He stabbed my father with a bamboo spear
saying he shouldn't waste bullets on him.
Honey!
I was hiding under the floor
but I saw the whole thing.
If I had tried to defend my family,
do you think I could have saved my mother?
I could have saved my sister.
Because she died instead of me.
Brother!
Do you want to know what Hell is?
It's someone murdering your family
while you stand helplessly by and watch.
Not able to make a sound.
That's Hell.
What will you do?
I'm sorry.
Please don't let them hurt my uncle.
Thank you for believing in me.
Father, the Pigeon has finally sent post.
"...3 more detectives involved in the murder."
Hello.
Pastor! Pastor!
Get away from here, Pastor!
Get in there! Find him.
Come on.
-Run, hurry.
-But Pastor...
Come on.
This is a place of God!
Violence will not be tolerated here.
What are you doing?
Where is Kim Jung-Nam?
Get him.
Hurry.
Open it.
"Memorial service for the victims of Gwangju"
In commemoration of
the Gwangju Uprising,
"11:30AM May 18, 1987"
we'll make an important announcement
in God's holy temple.
"Kim Seung-hoon / Priest"
"Catholic Priests' Association for Justice"
The truth behind the death of Park Jong-chul
was covered up by authorities.
The persons responsible for his murder
are in fact...
Inspector Cho Han-kyung,
Anti-communist Division 2-5-2-1
Senior Police Officer Lee Jeong-ho
Inspector Hwang Jung-woong
Assistant Inspector Ban Geum-gon
Assistant Inspector Kang Jin-gyu
"Great Koreans, to the great Korean way..."
Hold him properly, dammit!
Jong-chul, do you know where you are?
Even if you die here, no one will ever know.
So just tell us where he is.
I really don't know.
I swear.
Looks like we'll hear the end
of our national anthem.
Fourth verse.
Stop saying you don't know.
No!
No, please!
Get up, you bastard!
I don't wanna die.
"With this spirit and this mind..."
The fate of our future
towards democracy and humanity
depends on this case.
May 1 8, 1 987
Catholic Priests' Association for Justice
Send the pictures, now.
Yeah, the cops that tortured
and killed Park are
Officer Lee Jeong-ho,
Inspector Hwang Jung-woong.
He's not here.
Let's go.
Director!
Director.
Level 1 alert! Level 1 alert!
The meeting will be
at the Commissioner's office?
Yes sir.
Burn it all.
Everything.
Hurry up!
Hurry, guys!
-Let's hit the bar after work.
-Sounds good.
Inspector Hwang.
What brings you here?
Long time no see.
Goddammit!
You bastards!
Let go of me!
Get them out of here.
Goddammit!
Did you know
there were 5 officers involved in the torture?
I have no idea.
How can you not know?
ls this part of a cover-up?
I said I know nothing of it.
The order came from above, didn't it?
Shut up, you commie!
Any comments, Director?
You paid the officers
$1 00,000 to take the fall!
I secured the families' testimonies.
Where did you get the money?
Cover up of torture, murder,
fabrication of evidence.
You're over.
Sir!
"Final decisions on Park case"
"Pin Director Park and 3 detectives
with Park Jong-chul's death"
"Approved by President"
"3:00PM May 30, 1 987"
This place is swarming with rats.
Good to see your faces again.
Call me if you need a lawyer.
Have a good day.
Let's go.
Get your ass over to the square.
It's impossible to cover all of this, Chief!
Cover the universities and public squares. Go!
Yes sir!
Photographers!
At 6PM, all churches will sound their bells,
and cars are going to honk horns.
Get plenty of pictures!
-Yes sir!
-You got it!
Move!
Hello.
Sis.
Why are you crying?
Everything okay?
ls Yeon-hee okay?
Evening papers!
"Student hit by CS canister
in critical condition"
"5:00PM Jun 9, 1 987"
Long live democracy!
Down with dictatorship!
Raise guns!
Fire!
Ju-yeol!
Down with the torturers!
Down with the military regime!
Rise, 40 million citizens!
Bring down the killer regime!
Down with the torturers!
Bring back, Park Jong-chul!
Han-yeol! Han-yeol!
Long live democracy!
Down with dictatorship!
Another student is hurt by the police!
Let's all go to the city hall!
Citizens unite!
Bring down the military regime!
Down with the dictatorship!
No more lying administration!
Bring down the military regime!
Unite, 40 million citizens!
Bring down the dictatorial regime!
"Until that day when the waters
of the East Sea run dry"
"and Mount Baekdusan is worn away,"
"May God preserve our country,
our long-living homeland!"
Everybody, come up.
Another student is hurt by the police.
Let's send our support to Han-yeol.
Come on up!
"Great Koreans, to the great Korean way,
stay always true!"
Long live democracy!
Down with dictatorship!
1 987: WHEN THE DAY COMES
"On June 29, 1 987,
President Chun's administration"
"declared a direct election via popular vote."
"Lee Han-yeol was hospitalized"
"but died on July 5, 1 987."
"More than a million people
gathered for his funeral service."
"It won't be a mere night's dream"
"When our long suffering ends"
"My brother's eyes will stream"
"tears that flow"
"into a long river"
"made with laborious sweat"
"A dream of waves of justice"
"breaking in the vast ocean of peace"
"Daejeon"
"Daegu"
"Gwangju"
"Chuncheon"
"Busan"
"When the day comes"
"Jun 9, 1 987"
"my lost brothers' faces"
all the painful memories
and my short-lived youth
won't be a lost cause
"When the day comes"
"Lee Han-yeol's memorial service"
"my lost brothers' faces"
"all the painful memories"
"and the agonizing wait"
"won't be a lost cause"
"When the day comes"
"Inside the vague and faint fog"
"the path is ahead"
"A path like a rainbow far away"
"that feels close as if I can catch it"
"I wonder if it's waiting for me somewhere"
"I look around but I can't find it"
"My dear, please be my strength"
"So I can find this path"
"that is given to me"
"My dear, make a path for me"
"my path that is veiled"
A JANG JOON-HWAN FILM